{
    "id": "6e29e9b197fc4597b6ec957854b06d40",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "……………………… you take it or leave it.",
            "description": "Either or is used to present an unavoidable choice between two alternatives.",
            "answers": [
                "Either",
                "Neither",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor must come soon, ………………………. the patient will die.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "nor",
                "or",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. the doctor does not arrive soon, the patient will die.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t meet you tomorrow, ……………………….. I have an important appointment.",
            "description": "For can refer to the reason for something in a formal style. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "so",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………….. they played well, they could not win.",
            "description": "Even though is similar to though but it is more emphatic.",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "Even if",
                "Even though"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know …………………………. I will have time or not.",
            "description": "We use whether or if to introduce an yes/no question, but whether is preferred in the structure whether .. or not.",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We started early …………………………… we would not get stuck in traffic.",
            "description": "So that indicates purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "such that",
                "so that",
                "so as to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I shall lend you my camera ……………………………. you return it tomorrow.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "provided that",
                "on condition that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The passengers got off the bus …………………………… it stopped.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as long as",
                "as soon as",
                "no sooner than"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He speaks ………………………….. he is a genius.",
            "description": "As if and as though are used to say what a situation seems like.",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. I become a millionaire, I will always be a socialist.",
            "description": "Even if refers to the future. Even though refers to the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "Even if",
                "Even though",
                "Though"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… breaking his arm, he hurt his leg.",
            "description": "All of these expressions mean the same.",
            "answers": [
                "As well as",
                "In addition to",
                "Besides",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        }
    ]
}